[Music]
Hi everyone, this is Ravi. Welcome to
Tricentis Taska automation tutorial. As
you all know, I have already published
75 YouTube videos covering beginner's
level, intermediate level, and advanced
level concepts of tricentis tasks. From
few videos onwards have started teaching
you the realtime scenarios where you
might encounter different types of
obstacles while automating the test
cases and how can we solve those
obstacles by using tricentis
tasks. Please do subscribe to the
channel click on bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos. Don't forget to like and
share the video. Thank
you. This is our lesson 76 in terms of
overall tricentes tasks automation
tutorial and this is obstacle 34 in
terms of realtime scenarios. So in this
lesson I'm going to teach you how can we
solve an obstacle where you need to
store the baseline table which will have
n number of rows and n number of columns
and then you need to compare this stored
baseline table content with the same
table but the content has been changed.
So now how can I
identify what kind of content and what
content in which row and which column
the content has been changed in the
table. So that I'm going to do by using
table baseline comparison. So now let us
go and see in detail what is the
obstacle that we are going to solve for.
So here is the obstacle list that we
keep working from past few videos
onwards and today's obstacle is find the
changed cell. This is the name of your
obstacle and which is categorized as
medium. Let us go for it to see the
details of obstacle. What it is saying?
Click show change table to change the
value of one random
cell. Find the cell and enter the row,
column, original value and changed value
into the text boxes showing here. Use
task R to find this cell. So values can
be entered manually. There is no need to
automate this step. So what it is saying
here if you see this is your original
table which has n number of
columns and then n number of
rows. If I click on show changed table.
So this is the same table but the
content has been changed. What content
that has been changed?
randomly some specific cell content will
be
changed. If I click on show original
table, there is one cell which has a
different value compared to the original
table and changed table. So now you need
to
identify what is the cell that has
changed from these n number of
cells. As soon as I show change table,
so this is the table where one cell
value has been changed. We don't know
what cell value has been changed. It is
very difficult to find with your human
eye. So we can use
tricentistosa to compare the tables
between original table and change table.
So for that let us go to
tricestosca and let us start scanning
the objects. So what are the objects
that we need to scan in this case? In
this case you just need to scan your
table. So here right click on obstacles
folder select scan application.
Now select the application that you
would like to scan and click on scan
button. So now what is the table that we
need to cap? What is the table that we
need to capture? So this is the table
that we need to capture. Select the
table and do I need to capture all these
edit boxes? So these you need not to
capture. As soon as you identify which
row, which column and what is your
original value and what is your changed
value in the cell, you can just enter
this manually. So that's why I just need
this table. And now change the module
name with the obstacle name here. Copy
this and then paste the obstacle name
here. And now save your
module. Then close your Xcan. Let us go
back to
Tricentesa and come down to
bottom. So this is the new obstacle that
we captured. Double click on this
obstacle to make sure the objects are
available. So I can see here now table
row column I can see the table is
available. Now let us go back to our
obstacle test case folder left side
right click on this obstacle folder and
create test case and then here we
already copied the obstacle name. I'm
going to paste the same obstacle name
and then double click on test case. Now
let us start automating. To automate the
test case, you need to drag this table
and then drop onto your
obstacle. And
now let us expand this one. So to
perform table
comparison what we need to do first you
need to capture the baseline table. How
can I capture the baseline table? Let's
again go to original table. Let me click
on try again. First, I need to capture
the original table. This is my original
table, right? And this original table is
my baseline table. What I'm going to do
here to capture the baseline table,
right click on this table and then
select create baseline.
As soon as you select create baseline,
it's going to start capturing this
entire table content. All rows, all
columns. You can see it captured 10% of
your table. It is basically capturing
the entire content of this particular
original
table. It takes couple of seconds to
complete capturing the entire table,
rows, columns and the content.
So now you can see here table baseline
successfully created. Click on okay. If
you go back here and expand this see now
it says table compare. It says the
baseline has been created at 15th
March 8:24 sorry 15th March
108 p.m. So that means
now to compare the table. Let's go back
to the application as we captured the
baseline table. Now I'm going to click
on show change table. So now this is the
change table where one of the cell value
has been changed. So how can I identify
which cell has been changed? Now let's
go back to tricentistosa.
You need to run this test case again.
Why? Once it creates the baseline, now
it is marked as table compare. So that
means whenever you run this test case,
it's going to compare the existing
display
table with the baseline table that we
captured at this time stamp. So let me
right click and run in scratchbook.
So now it started comparing the original
table with the changed
table. So your test case is going to
fail because when it compares both the
tables, it's going to identify that one
of the cell is not matching. So if you
see here it says column this in row 23
was modified. What is the expected
value? This is your original value and
this is your actual value. So let's copy
this entire thing into a
notepad.
Let's paste it here. So what is the row?
Row number is 23. Let's go back to
our obstacle. So here I'm going to enter
23 and what is the column that has
changed? This is the column right? So
basically these are the column headers
somewhere we have that column here. Okay
this is the column and what is your
original value? This is your expected
value. That means the baseline table has
this value in the
cell. And then what is the changed
value? The changed
table
has this value in this
cell. Now if I submit this should be
able to solve the problem
successfully. As soon as you submit it
should say your automation problem
solved successfully. But however it is
not working right now. But that is how
you can solve the obstacle to compare
the tables with your baseline and the
change table. So if you have any
queries, leave your queries in the
comment box. I'll try to respond to your
queries. Thank you. Hope you all
understand how to solve an obstacle
where you need to store the baseline
table and then compare the baseline
table content with the changed table
content. Please do subscribe to the
channel, click on bell icon, you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos. Don't forget to like and
share the video. Thank you.
[Music]